It's good to be king.
Three Kings is a action, comedy, war film directed by David O. Russell.
A group of American soldiers stationed in Iraq at the end of the Gulf War find a map they believe will take them to a huge cache of
stolen Kuwaiti gold hidden near their base, and they embark on a secret mission that's destined to change everything.
Archie Gates, played by George Clooney.
Troy Barlow, played by Mark Wahlberg.
Chief Elgin, played by Ice Cube.
Conrad Vig, played by Spike Jonze.
Amir Abdullah, played by Cliff Curtis.
Adriana Cruz, played by Nora Dunn.
Three Kings is a 1999 black comedy war film written and directed by David O.
Russell from a story by John Ridley.
It stars George Clooney, Mark Wahlberg, Ice Cube, and Spike Jonze as four American soldiers on a gold heist that takes
place during the 1991 uprisings in Iraq against Saddam Hussein following the end of the First Gulf War.
Three Kings was released on October 1, 1999, in the United
States and on January 13, 2000 in Australia.
Warner Bros.
distributed the film worldwide, while Roadshow Films
distributed the film in Australia and New Zealand.
The film received critical acclaim and grossed $107.7
million against a $48 million budget.
The film explores themes of rescue, gold, gulf war, three kings, iraq.
The tone is lighthearted.